# **Samuel Tracy**

Phone: (916) 764-9002 Email: stracy@g.harvard.edu Web: https://seasamgo.github.io

Ph.D. student in Biostatistics at Harvard University focusing on methods for failure time data and single-cell sequencing data. My advisor is Dr. Guo-Cheng Yuan. Interests include sampling techniques, optimization theory, missingness, clustering methods, and dimensionality reduction. I am also an advocate for open-source development, reproducible research and diversity in STEM.

### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. Biostatistics	Harvard University	$2019^{1}$
M.A. Biostatistics	Harvard University	2016
B.S. Applied Mathematics, magna cum laude	UC San Diego	2014

#### **SKILLS**

R, Stata, MATLAB – highly proficient Java, C++, Python – proficient

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Research Consultant** *Harvard University, Boston, MA* 09/2017 - present

Department of Biostatistics Consulting Center

**Student Intern** *CTRI, San Diego, CA* 04/2013 - 06/2013

Clinical data visualization and analysis

# TEACHING EXPERIENCE

**Teaching Assistant** Harvard University, Boston, MA 01/2016 - present

Introductory Biostatistics courses

**Instructor/Administrator** StatStart, Boston, MA 01/2015 - 08/2017

Summer high school program in statistical computing for minorities in STEM

**Teaching Assistant** *UC San Diego, San Diego, CA* 09/2013 - 06/2014

MATH 10 Calculus series

**Academic Liaison** Fallbrook High, Fallbrook, CA 01/2013 - 03/2013

Tutor and liaison through the UC San Diego Educational Studies Department

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Talbot, O., Ocampo, A., Tracy, S., Mosesso, K., Rahman, A., and Pagano, M. StatStart 2015. *ASA: The Statistics Teacher Network*, 87: 4-8, 2016.

1

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup>anticipated

#### **PROJECTS**

Chen, T., Tracy, S., Uno, H. Minimal-area confidence bands for failure time data.

Tracy, S., Dries, R., Yuan, G.C. scRNA-seq dropout imputation via subsampling of genes.

Tracy, S., Yuan, G.C. Scoring lineage prediction with single-cell data.

### SOFTWARE

Co-creator and maintainer of the R package optband (on CRAN and GitHub), a package for statistical confidence bands applied to failure time data and optimized by area.

## REFERENCES

# Yuan, Guo-Cheng

Associate Professor, Department of Biostatistics, Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health Address: 360 Longwood Ave, Room 1060, Boston, MA 02215

Tel: 617-582-8532 Email: gcyuan@jimmy.harvard.edu

# Xu, Ronghui

Professor, Department of Mathematics, University of California, San Diego

Address: 9500 Gilman Drive #0112, La Jolla, CA 92093

Tel: 858-534-6380 Email: rxu@ucsd.edu

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup>anticipated